Finding Aid for Rensis Likert papers, 1929-1983.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Published Works
  - 1943
    - "Attitude Research in the Department of Agriculture" (by Hans Skott) (Box 22)
  - 1944
    - "Research: New Weapon of War" (Box 22)
  - 1946
    - "Five Views on the Consumption Function" (with George Katona) (Box 22)
  - 1947
    - "The Sample Interview Survey" (Box 22)
  - 1948
    - "Opinion Studies and Government Policy" (Box 22)
    - "The Polls: Straw Votes or Scientific Instruments" (Box 22)
    - "Public Opinion Polls" (Box 22)
    - "Why Opinion Polls Were So Wrong" (interview in U.S. News and World Report) (Box 22)
  - 1949
    - "Human Relations at Work" (Box 22)
    - "Standards for Appraising Psychological Research" (with Dale Wolfle, Donald Marquis, and Robert Sears) (Box 22)
  - 1951
    - "Are You Worried About the Atomic Bomb?" (transcript of radio show panelists) (Box 22)
    - "Motivational Dimensions of Administration" (Box 22)
  - 1952
    - "Findings of Research on Management and Leadership" (Box 22)
    - "The Need for Research on the Communication of Research Results" (with Floyd Mann) (Box 22)
  - 1954
    - "A Neglected Factor in Communications" (Box 22)
    - "Research on Consumer Motivation" (Box 22)
    - "Understanding Human Behavior" (Box 22)
  - 1956
    - "Motivation and Morale in Public Service" (with Stanley Seashore) (Box 22)
  - 1957
    - "Behavioral Research: A Guide for Effective Action" (Box 22)
    - "The Changing Role of the Company President" (Box 22)
  - 1958
    - "Effective Supervision: An Adaptive and Relative Approach" (Box 22)
    - "Management Implications of Recent Social Science Research-A Symposium" (Box 22)
    - "Measuring Organizational Performance" (Box 22)
  - 1959
    - "How to Raise Productivity 20%" (Box 22)
    - "Motivational Approach to Management Development" (Box 22)
  - 1960
    - "The Dual Function of Statistics" (Box 22)
  - 1961
    - "Managing Successfully for Today AND Tomorrow" (Box 22)
  - 1962
    - "New Patterns in Sales Management" (Box 22)
    - "Supervision" (Box 22)
  - 1963
    - "Improving Management Through Continuing Research" (Box 22)
    - "Making Cost Control Work" (with Stanley Seashore) (Box 22)
    - "Trends Toward A World-Wide Theory of Management" (Box 22)
  - 1964
    - "Current Research in Management and Its Application to Administration of Medical Centers" (Box 22)
  - 1966
    - "ISR and the Capstone University" (Box 22)
    - "The University Setting" (Box 22)
  - 1968
    - "Diagnose Your Teaching Role" (Box 22)
  - 1969
    - "How to Increase A Firm's Lead Time In Recognizing and Dealing with Problems of Managing Its Human Organization" (with David Bowers and Richard Norman) (Box 22)
    - "Human Resource Accounting" (Box 22)
    - "Organizational Theory and Human Resource Accounting" (with David Bowers) (Box 22)
    - "The Relationship Between Management Behavior and Social Structure" (Box 22)
  - 1971
    - "Human Asset Accounting for Air Force Organizations" (Box 22)
    - "Human Organizational Measurements: Key to Financial Success" (Box 22)
    - "Human Resource Accounting-A Human Organizational Measurement Approach" (Box 22)
    - "Increasing Organizational Success Through Lead Time Management" (Box 22)
  - 1972
    - "Characteristics of Effective Organizations" (Box 22)
    - "Conflict Strategies Related to Organizational Theories and Management Systems" (Box 22)
  - 1973
    - "Improving the Accuracy of P/L Reports by Estimating the Change in Dollar Value of the Human Organization" (with David Bowers) (Box 22)
    - "The Organizational Climate for Successful Innovation" (Box 22)
  - 1978
    - "Managing an Interdisciplinary Research Institute: The Institute for Social Research" (Box 22)
  - 1979
    - "From Production-and Employee-Centeredness to System 1-4" (Box 22)
  - Reprints of articles, speeches, articles and books by RL (Box 26)
- Miscellaneous Project Files
  - SRC. Office of Naval Research, Advisory Panel on Human Relations (Box 27)
  - SRC. Federal Reserve System. Board of Governors (Box 27)
  - BAE. National Research Council. Committee on Food Habits. (Box 27)
  - BAE. Federal Committee on Economic Statistics. Committee on Adequacy (Box 27)
  - Army Services Forces. Information and Education Division. (Box 27)
  - U.S. Forest Service (Box 27)
  - U.S. Treasury Department (Box 27)
  - Public Reaction to the Atomic Bomb and World Affairs (Cornell University, International Studies), 1947 (Box 27)
  - Miscellaneous (1940s work), 0.3 linear feet (Box 27)
- Photographs
  Photographs include pictures taken in Japan relating to study of the effects of bombing on Japanese morale undertaken for the United States Strategic and photos from an agricultural survey exhibit.
  - Morale Division work in Japan, 1945 (Box 27)
  - Agricultural survey exhibit, 1940 (Box 27)